RESUME

Kala W/o Jayaseelan

No .4, 3rd St, Anna nagar, Madambakkam, East Tambaram,

Chennai-600126.

Email id: kala.engg09@gmail.com

Mobile no: +91-9962462561

Dear Sir/Madam,

Please accept this letter and the accompanying resume as an expression of my interest in a position with your esteemed organization.

As my Resume indicates, I am having 11 Years' experience in QUALITY ENGINEERING FIELD and I would like to begin employment with an organization in which my effective performance will be with recognition and growth.

I am Proficient in various Quality Fields like, developing and implementing statistical process control (SPC), Generation of CAPA, process FMEA, Maintaining All **MR (IATF-TS16949)** Docs and ability to work well in a team environment.

I am certain I could make significant contributions to your organization, and I would Welcome the opportunity to meet with you to discuss how my education and abilities might best be employed by your esteemed organization.

And also I have attached my resume with this letter.

Thanking you for your consideration. I am looking forward for your response.

Sincerely,

Kala J

KALA J

ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING,
ARULMIGU MEENAKSHI AMMAN COLLEGE OF

ENGINEERING, ANNA UNIVERSITY.

CONTACT DETAILS

No.4, 3rd St, Anna nagar,

Madambakkam, East Tambaram,

Chennai-600126.

Email id: kala.engg09@gmail.com Mobile no: +91-9962462561

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

To deliver my duties to the at most satisfaction of the superiors and subordinates and flexible to any type of work to reach responsible position in future, work for the betterment of the company in any circumstances.

EDUCATIONAL DETAILS:

COURSE	INSTITUTION	YEAR OF PASSING	PERCENTAGE/CGPA
S.S.L.C	Govt Higher Secondary School, Krishnagiri.	2002	74%
H.S.C	Govt Higher Secondary School, Krishnagiri.	2005	76%
B.E	Arulmigu Meenakshi Amman college of engg	2010	63%

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Quality engineer with 11 years' experience in Electrical Wire Hardness noise avoiding material manufacturing industry for customers like Daimler India Chennai, All Motherson Group, Samsung Etc.,. Proficient in various Quality Fields like, developing and implementing statistical process control (SPC), Generation of CAPA PPT, AOI-ISIR, Customer Complaints, Supplier meet presentation and design and process FMEA and ability to work well in a team environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

COMPANY 1 : GSV Microtech Privated limited.,

Kundrathur main rd, madhanandapuram, Chennai.

ROLE : Quality control engineer

DURATION : 2 years (Mar2010 to Nov 2012)

LOCATION : Chennai

COMPANY DETAILS: GSV now manufactures Flow Meters, Conductivity Meters, pH indicators, Temperature Indicators, Ultrasonic Level indicators, Process Indicators, Power/Energy Meters, Power Factor correction subsystems, Dedicated PLC's, Motorized valves, Electronic metering pumps, Data acquisition systems and more.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Incoming inspection(IIR) of BOM
- Online inspection for PCB assembly and testing, panel board assembly and stage wise process inspection.
- Software program testing for sensor and USB cable.
- ISO Docs maintenance and conduction of audit.
- PDI inspection and final test report submission to customer.
- Adhering to system procedures (NCS Trend Downwards).
- Working towards nil / less customer complaints.
- By delivering products on time.
- Always aiming for Continual Improvements (2 Kaizen / Quarter)

COMPANY 2: Butterfly Gandhimathi Appliances Itd,.- Motors Section.

Pudupakkam village vandalur-kelambakkam road ,Chennai

ROLE : Quality team leader

DURATION: 1 years(Jan 2013 to Nov 2013)

LOCATION : Chennai

COMPANY DETAILS: Swaminathan enterprises is a motor manufacturing unit manufactures motors such as table top motors, washer motors and general purpose motors.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Monitoring relevant information and preparing statistical reports.
- Rejection analysis and in-house ppm monitoring.
- Layout inspection to ensure product dimensions is within the specification and conducting inspection for incoming material as per standards.
- Attain and receive customer complaints and find out root cause and raise CA/PA.
- Tracking and monitoring customer delivery with satisfaction level, customer end rejections with agreed targets.
- Generation of Pareto report chart, why why analysis, cause and effect diagrams for rejection analysis, kaizen activities for continuous improvement and also poka yoke.
- Generation of PPAP and FMEA
- Performing capability studies (SPC).

COMPANY 3 : Monarch tapes and adhesives (i) pvt ltd.,Gokul colony,karanaipucherry,chennai 126

ROLE : Quality Management Reporting (MR)

LOCATION : Chennai

DURATION : 8 Years (2013 to 13th Feb2021)

COMPANY DETAILS: Monarch is the largest manufacturer of different polymer foam base self adhesive and non-adhesive products, Cotton pad rolls, sheets and die cuts.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Responsible for all customer related activities.
- Responsible for all customer related documentations.
- Responsible for process and product Audit.

- Handling customer complaint and CAPA
- Responsible for reduction of customer end rejection.
- Leading the PDI team to achieve the Zero customer rejection.
- Providing periodic training for quality team.
- Responsible for continual improvements.
- Responsible for 3 months once customers end PPT presentation.
- Responsible for reduce customer end rejection &prevent customer complaints.
- Responsible for TS 16949 internal and external NC closed activities.
- Responsible for new product developments activities.
- Responsible for Tool validation maintaining activities
- Rejection analysis and in-house ppm monitoring.
- Responsible for customer end complaints and CAR closing activities

PERSONAL TRAITS:

- Ability to mould oneself according to the needs of the organization.
- Positive attitude and pleasing personality.
- Always striving to work hard to achieve objectives.
- Can be able to perform outstandingly under work pressure.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Spouse's name : Jayaseelan M

Nationality : Indian

A.S.L. : 33/female/Chennai

D.O.B : 1.06.1987

Mother tongue : Tamil

Languages Known: Tamil, Telugu, Kanada and English.

Total years of : 11 years Experience

ACKNOWLEDGEMENT:

I do hereby declare that the information furnished in this document is true and many thanks for your valuable time given to my Curriculum Vitae.

Place:Chennai

Date: (kala J)